## ALOK BHAWANKAR

SOFTWARE ENGINEER 

◆ PUNE, INDIA 

+91 9834825542

## • DETAILS •

Pune India +91 9834825542 alok.bhawankar@gmail.com

# • LINKS • alokbhawankar.dev

github.com/alr0cks linkedin.com/in/alokbhawankar/

#### o SKILLS o

Python - FastAPI, Flask

Cloud Service and Data-warehouse - AWS, Snowflake,

BigData - SQL, ETL/ELT, Data-Lake, Data-API, Redis

JavaScript - Node.js

Containers and Orchestration - Docker, Kubernetes & Helm

Infrastructure Management -Terraform

Other - Java, C++, Linux, Git

## PROFILE

I'm a driven and self-motivated Software Developer with DevOps and Data Engineering experience. I have successfully built and deployed multiple projects, as well as contributed to open source projects and continue to do so. I have a keen interest in designing, building highly concurrent applications, and deploying them at scale.

## EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

#### Data Engineer at VIBRENT HEALTH, Pune

July 2021 - Present

- I was responsible for planning, developing, and maintaining scalable and efficient data-engineering projects involving various data systems and pipelines built using ELT/ETL tools in different frameworks and tech-stack.
- Analyzing and organizing raw data, developing snow-pipes to ingest data into a data warehouse, creating API endpoints for the data-lake according to business needs and objectives.
- Automating tasks for more efficient and reliable management of services and projects.

## Software Development Intern at TRANSOFY PVT. LTD., Mumbai

November 2020 — February 2021

- I was responsible to deploy and maintain network applications.
- Create back-end API and component in node.js for seamless exchange of data between services.

## EDUCATION

B.Tech in Computer Science and Technology, MIT WORLD PEACE UNIVERSITY, Pune 2017-2021

## **★** PERSONAL PROJECTS

#### MITM Toolkit

A toolkit that allows users to exploit the victim's PC using a Man-in-the-Middle attack and perform various vulnerability scans.

## **Telegram Group Management Bot**

A telegram bot is used to manage groups and their members. It consists of many different features.

## Web-Pentest-Toolkit

A toolkit that allows you to test your website for information gathering and various vulnerabilities such as Cross-Site Scripting, SQL Injection, Bypass Login, etc.

#### **Home Automation using RPI**

It is voice-controlled home automation where users can control and monitor their home appliances using an Android phone and raspberry pi.

## **→** COMMUNITY PARTICIPATION

Organizer and Core Member at The S.C.R.I.P.T Group

Lead Workshop lecturer on Ethical Hacking